<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Robert Mack Group is to be your best resource for  real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Robert Mack Group, your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:41:34 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons Why Now Is the Time to Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gEUaik41NxI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;My five reasons why it may be a wonderful time to sell your home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is now a great time to sell? Are you a seller trying to time the market perfectly? Honestly, it’s impossible to time the market just right. For most of my clients who have timed the market perfectly, it was simply luck. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we approach the holidays, clients say they’re a bit concerned: Thanksgiving is around the corner, Christmas is coming up, New Year’s, elections, and so on. They ask, “Do you think we should wait until next year? Do you think we’ll be able to get more for our home?” I tell everyone the same thing: I don’t have a crystal ball. All I can do is provide the best guidance based on the market now, present my estimations of what’s going to happen, and what I’m seeing in the market place, but it’s never a guarantee. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have five reasons why &lt;strong&gt;selling now is potentially better than selling in the future.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a wonderful time to sell right now. However, remember: This is your home, you don’t have to sell it, you don’t have to accept any offer. Even if an offer comes in at full price, you don’t ever have to accept it. So, let’s do what we need to do to prepare the home, and if we get an awesome price when we list it, then great—you were able to fulfill your goals. If for some reason we can’t get an awesome price for your home, we’ll try again in the new year, but at least you gave it a try and there are no regrets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s impossible to time the market just right.%20http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-why-now-is-the-time-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s impossible to time the market just right.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the five reasons it’s favorable to sell right now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Less competition.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people think that it’s a bad time to sell right now, and without consulting a real estate agent to learn their options, they’re deciding to list in the new year. Those sellers will not be your competition right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. We know the market now.&lt;/strong&gt; We know that right now the market is wonderful, so let’s take advantage of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Rates are historically low.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers are still submitting offers on properties and many homes are receiving multiple offers, which means there’s still a lot of demand for excellent homes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Buyers have more time to look.&lt;/strong&gt; People have more time to look for homes during the holidays. They often have time off for each holiday coming up. When buyers have time off, that’s when they want to go see homes. Right now presents a wonderful opportunity for them to look at properties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Buyers are motivated during the holidays.&lt;/strong&gt; If buyers weren’t motivated, they’d be spending time with their family, traveling, or doing other things. They wouldn’t be searching for homes. They have a clear reason to be looking during the holidays; maybe tax reasons, to buy before the end of the year, and so on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you’ve made it this far, I want to give you a bonus tip! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Take a chance!&lt;/strong&gt; Most people are not going to list now; they plan on listing in 2020. If you list in the new year there’s going to be much more competition, much less demand. If you’re thinking about selling, speak to an agent, understand your options, take a chance. If you don’t get what you want, you always have 2020. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever want to talk about your options, please email or call me. I would love to help you. If you have any video ideas you want me to talk about in the future, send those my way as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 15:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-why-now-is-the-time-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-why-now-is-the-time-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Were You Unsuccessful in Selling Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8lZAvdLBgAo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your home previously did not sell, we have the options you need.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you try to sell your home but were unsuccessful? Are you looking for more options? Whether the home was withdrawn, canceled, or expired, you may still need to sell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s probably happening is you’re getting battered with mail, texts, emails, and phone calls from dozens of agents telling you why they’re the best, why your last agent was horrible, and why they’re the ones who can help you achieve your goals. There are 16,000 agents in Orange County and last year only 400 of them sold 10 homes or more. &lt;strong&gt;95% to 98% of these agents that are contacting you do not have the expertise required&lt;/strong&gt; to help you get your home sold for the best price and in the time you want it because they haven’t been in the business long enough. This is not a favorable market for someone who does not have a strategy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to make sure that you do your due diligence. If you are speaking to different agents you should be asking the right questions. Many agents are calling because they want your listing, but what you’re likely looking for are options. “Why didn’t my home sell? What is the next step? What can I do differently to get my home sold? Who should I hire?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is not a favorable market for someone who does not have a strategy.%20http://localhost:4000/were-you-unsuccessful-in-selling-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is not a favorable market for someone who does not have a strategy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk to a few agents to assess how you can do better. &lt;strong&gt;My team and I specialize in assisting clients to sell their homes when previous agents failed.&lt;/strong&gt; The one thing we pride ourselves on is that we aren’t calling because we want your listing but because we want to help. When we are offering help, we’ll walk you through different potential scenarios to present you with options. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this market, sometimes you have to get inventive. Interest rates are great, homes are still selling for amazing prices, but buyers are dubious. The recession is coming, that’s the talk of the town. So what can we do to design a listing strategy that’s going to be “recession-proof”? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you tried to sell in the past and weren’t successful send me an email or call me, we’d love to lay out all of your options. If you have specific questions but aren’t ready to meet yet please contact us anyway. We’re happy to help in whatever way we can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 15:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-you-unsuccessful-in-selling-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/were-you-unsuccessful-in-selling-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Focusing on Price or Monthly Payment?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hn1VJ0odXEk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buyers: Are you too focused on the price of the home rather than your monthly payment? Let’s discuss this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering your budget for buying a home, are you concentrating on price or monthly payment? Early in my career one of my mentors told me that price is a one-time thing but monthly payments are a monthly thing. That’s what’s going to determine your affordability. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times the buyers we meet are sticking to a specific number when &lt;strong&gt;the truth is that different loan programs can offer you different price options.&lt;/strong&gt; Based on your risk tolerance, you could potentially afford more home and still have a lower monthly payment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Price is a one-time thing but monthly payments are a monthly thing.%20http://localhost:4000/are-you-focusing-on-price-or-monthly-payment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Price is a one-time thing but monthly payments are a monthly thing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I want buyers to consider is that many people are talking about a recession. There are areas in Orange County where we have begun to see some prices dropping. Many clients ask, “If the prices are going down why don’t we just wait until they drop 3% to 5% and then buy?” The reason why that may not be the best approach is that interest rates play a huge role in what your monthly payment will be. Every time the rates go up 1%, property values fall 10%. What you may find is that the rates will go up higher and faster than the property values will come down. So &lt;strong&gt;you could get stuck buying a home for a better price but actually have a higher monthly payment,&lt;/strong&gt; which doesn’t make sense. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a buyer, the best option for you, no matter when you’re thinking of buying, is to speak to a lender. There are no costs, obligations, or strings attached. A lender can offer you more options. Options help us assess what the next best step moving may be for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer and you want to talk to a lender please call or send me an email. We would love to open up our network to help you figure out what your next step might be. If you have any video ideas you want me to talk about in the future, send those my way!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 15:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-focusing-on-price-or-monthly-payment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-focusing-on-price-or-monthly-payment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Outside Forces Impact Our Orange County Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cMkb3yZ_Xj8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many people think that facts and figures are the best way to judge the market, but there’s more to the story than this. Let’s discuss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often when people think about the state of our real estate market, they tend to take into account the obvious factors like the number of available homes, the political climate, local employment trends, and other such points of interest. However, what people sometimes fail to consider is that there are also many external factors at play. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong: &lt;strong&gt;Keeping trends like interest rates and appreciation rates in mind is certainly a good idea, but it’s also important to account for human error.&lt;/strong&gt; Even real estate professionals can sometimes get the facts wrong. Let’s say you’re thinking of selling, but have been dragging your feet on making a move. By the time you get around to listing, there are suddenly four or five other properties for sale in your neighborhood. As unlikely as this might sound, it happens. There is no way to precisely predict what’s going to happen in our market—especially on a hyperlocal level. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National trends only reflect the average direction of various market conditions. Even though prices are rising across the country, overall, for example, prices are flattening out and even decreasing in certain areas of Orange County. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There’s simply no way to predict how the human element of our market will impact local real estate.%20http://localhost:4000/what-outside-forces-impact-our-orange-county-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There’s simply no way to predict how the human element of our market will impact local real estate.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is to take reports from the media with a grain of salt. &lt;strong&gt;The facts and figures that come out about our market only tell part of the story.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s simply no way to predict how the human element of our market will impact local real estate. Numbers don’t solely dictate the market—buyers, sellers, homeowners, and real estate agents play a major role, as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, even in light of recent recession rumors, our current market is still going strong. Inventory is plentiful and interest rates are low, meaning buyers have a lot of properties to choose from and have greater purchasing power to leverage during their search. This benefits sellers, as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even if our economy begins to slow, this doesn’t mean the housing market will do the same.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, many experts predict that home prices will continue to rise over the next 12 to 24 months, depending on where you live. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, now is the time to connect with a Realtor (like myself) to talk about your real estate goals in relation to what’s happening now. If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 11:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-outside-forces-impact-our-orange-county-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-outside-forces-impact-our-orange-county-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 2 Keys to Getting Top Dollar for Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UZGXT6hMnn8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your home’s list price and how it shows are the two keys to focus on if you want to sell it for top dollar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot that goes into selling a home for top dollar. First of all, you have to work with the right agent and the right team to make sure they assist you in executing your plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an agent though, you should know that are two keys to getting top dollar for your home: &lt;strong&gt;its list price and how it shows. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 92% of all buyers will see your home online before they visit it, and if it doesn’t look great online, they might not want to see it in person. More importantly, buyers are very picky when it comes to what they’re willing to spend money on these days, and buyer demand has dropped since it peaked earlier in the year. This is why &lt;strong&gt;you must price your home strategically.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=About 92% of all buyers will see your home online before they visit it, and if it doesn’t look great online, they might not want to see it in person.%20http://localhost:4000/the-2-keys-to-getting-top-dollar-for-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“About 92% of all buyers will see your home online before they visit it, and if it doesn’t look great online, they might not want to see it in person.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, the list price my team and I set for our clients isn’t necessarily the price we want to sell the home for—it’s the bait. What can we do knowing that every buyer wants a good deal? How can we price a home so that it gives buyers the impression that it’s a great deal? Also, how can we maximize its exposure? We know that if more buyers see your home, you have a better chance of attracting multiple offers. If your home’s price is aggressive and attractive, they’ll want to see it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s just step one, though, because if they walk in your door and don’t see something they love, that will lead to a huge disconnect. That’s why the next step is to &lt;strong&gt;make your home look like a model home&lt;/strong&gt;. It should look so nice that buyers fall in love with it instantaneously and feel compelled to make an offer. If you can make more than one buyer feel that way, you have a multiple-offer situation on your hand. All that’s left is to see who’s willing to pay the most for your home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about selling your home for top dollar or you have any other real estate questions I can answer, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you. Until then, happy selling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-2-keys-to-getting-top-dollar-for-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-2-keys-to-getting-top-dollar-for-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Really Better Off Waiting Until Next Year to Sell?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xf3rU1dQPKs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your home failed to sell recently, you’re not necessarily better off waiting until 2020 to try again. Here’s why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you tried selling your home in the recent past and your listing was withdrawn, canceled, or expired, you’re probably thinking you’d rather wait until 2020 to try listing again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talk to about 20 people a day who are in the same situation, and half of them say the same thing—either the market was no good, they didn’t get the price they wanted, or the holiday season is coming up and they don’t want to deal with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiting until the new year to list may be the right approach, but today I want to share a few reasons why it may not be. Right now, the market still has a lot of juice left for sellers. Although we’re experience a market shift, with the right strategy, you can recreate a great market for your home sale and earn a record price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wait until next year to sell, you’ll face a couple challenges. First of all, &lt;strong&gt;a lot of other sellers want to wait until the new year to list, too.&lt;/strong&gt; What do you think will happen if you wait until the new year to put your home on the market and all those other sellers do the same thing? That’s right—there will be a lot of inventory. More inventory means buyers have more choices, and when buyers have more choices, demand falls. When demand falls, you may net significantly less from your home sale than you would if you listed when there wasn’t as much inventory—especially in a shifting market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Right now, the market still has a lot of juice left for sellers.%20http://localhost:4000/are-you-really-better-off-waiting-until-next-year-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Right now, the market still has a lot of juice left for sellers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before you make a final decision, do yourself a favor: &lt;strong&gt;Reach out to a few agents and see what they’d be able to do for you if you listed again this year.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn’t cost you a thing and there are no obligations. If you meet with a few agents and then decide you still would rather wait until next year to sell, at least you did your due diligence. Who knows, you may find out that selling this year really does represent a better opportunity for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, the worst thing you can do is go into autopilot in terms of selling next year, find out it’s not a great market, and then regret the fact that you waited. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a fresh, modern approach to selling your home in 2019, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. My team and I are experts in getting homes sold that previously failed to sell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to speak with you. Until then, happy selling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 14:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-really-better-off-waiting-until-next-year-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-really-better-off-waiting-until-next-year-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Are You Willing to Sacrifice in Order to Buy a New Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KMqoNC9NjjM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buying a new home in our market means you may need to sacrifice. Here’s what I mean by that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you willing to sacrifice in order to buy a new home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our market tightens and shifts, buyers and sellers tend to get pickier. In the last few months, we’ve seen transactions where both parties came to a standstill during negotiations when they were just a few thousand dollars apart. I always tell my clients that if they’re spending upwards of $750,000 or $1 million on a property, a few thousand dollars shouldn’t stand in the way of them getting what they want. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of us, though—myself included—spend money on things that don’t help our bottom line.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, let’s say you buy a $5 Starbucks coffee for 15 days out of every month. That equates to $75 you’re spending each month on Starbucks coffee when you could be saving close to that amount by just making coffee at home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Think about what you’re willing to sacrifice for the greater good.%20http://localhost:4000/what-are-you-willing-to-sacrifice-in-order-to-buy-a-new-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Think about what you’re willing to sacrifice for the greater good.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were to spend an extra $10,000 on the home you want, your monthly mortgage payment would increase between $60 and $75 anyway, so &lt;strong&gt;think about what you’re spending money on that you could potentially eliminate&lt;/strong&gt; so that you can give yourself a better chance at affording that home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, think about what you’re willing to sacrifice for the greater good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you. Until then, happy selling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 14:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-you-willing-to-sacrifice-in-order-to-buy-a-new-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-are-you-willing-to-sacrifice-in-order-to-buy-a-new-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Would a Recession Mean for the Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HaCzkJAZF5I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a recession and how does it actually influence our real estate market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer the first question, a recession is when the GDP falls for two consecutive quarters. Sometimes it lasts just those two quarters, sometimes it lasts longer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer the second question, let’s look at some historical data. In 1980, we went through a recession and home prices appreciated by 6.1%. In 1981, we were still in the same recession, and once again, home prices appreciated—this time to the tune of 3.5%. In 1991, there was another recession, and home prices dropped just 1.9%. Then in 2001, during another recession, home prices rose 6.6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there’s a trend here: &lt;strong&gt;Just because we go through a recession, it doesn’t mean home prices will fall.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, in three of the five recessions we’ve been through in the past 40 years, home prices went up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In three of the five recessions we’ve been through in the past 40 years, home prices went up.%20http://localhost:4000/what-would-a-recession-mean-for-the-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In three of the five recessions we’ve been through in the past 40 years, home prices went up.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last recession we went through, as you might guess, was back in 2008, and home prices dropped 19.7%. The difference between that recession and all the others, though, is that it was caused specifically by the housing market. The market was naturally inflated by all the bad loans handed out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re a buyer or a seller sitting on the fence waiting to see if prices fall or the market crashes, let me put your mind at ease. Despite what the media might have you believe, &lt;strong&gt;real economists anticipate a 3% to 4% appreciation in the next couple of years.&lt;/strong&gt; Will the market shift at some point? Absolutely—the market is always correcting itself. The only way you’ll time the market, though, is if you get lucky. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer waiting for the recession to hit so you can get an amazing deal, that’s probably not going to happen. If you’re waiting for a better deal, that might happen, but don’t forget about interest rates. You might be able to get a home at a better price if you wait a couple of years, but if interest rates go from 3.5% to 5% during that time, you’ll still pay more per month for the same house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to talk more about this topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. Until then, happy selling!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 10:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-would-a-recession-mean-for-the-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-would-a-recession-mean-for-the-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Zillow’s Zestimates Accurate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IEl2KgzM_kE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you search for properties online, you’ll notice that most third-party sites (Trulia, Redfin, Zillow, etc.) offer some type of automated home valuation. By using valuations like Zillow’s Zestimate, you can get an idea of what your home is worth. However, &lt;strong&gt;they’re not as accurate as you might think. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clarify, most agents don’t like sites like Zillow because they can be considered a disruptor of the industry, but I’m a fan of them because I like the fact that so much information is transparent. I think this benefits sellers tremendously because, before these sites existed, Realtors held all the information. Many times, this information wouldn’t get to the right people and cause homes to sell for less than what they were worth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why the message about their inaccuracy? We put a North Tustin home on the market recently, and we were surprised by how big the difference was between its automated valuation and its real value. It’s located in a neighborhood where homes are selling between $1.2 million and $2 million, but Zillow said it was worth $847,000, while Redfin said it was worth over $1.3 million. That’s a $500,000 gap. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my business partner Ryan McMillan says, Zillow’s Zestimate is beneficial in that it allows consumers to gauge how much a property is worth, but they don’t take into account the fact that it’s an algorithm. You can’t really know what a home is worth until you take into consideration the state of the market, the home’s condition, and other factors. &lt;strong&gt;This is why consulting a real estate professional is the best way to determine your home’s value. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What a home is worth on paper and what a Realtor can sell it for are two very different things, which is why you must hire a Realtor to accurately assess your home’s value.%20http://localhost:4000/are-zillows-zestimates-accurate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What a home is worth on paper and what a Realtor can sell it for are two very different things, which is why you must hire a Realtor to accurately assess your home’s value.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zillow claims that their Zestimate has a 10% margin of error, meaning it’ll value a $1 million home for anywhere from $900,000 to $1.1 million. This is because, as we already said, it’s an algorithm that can’t account for a lot of important factors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider seven to 10 different factors before pricing a home for the market, and a home’s worth can also be altered based on the strategy the seller uses to get it sold. If you overprice your home, it might sit on the market and cause you to sell for less than what it’s worth. If you underprice it, you might create an auction effect that causes it to sell above its list price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, &lt;strong&gt;what a home is worth on paper and what a Realtor can sell it for are two very different things&lt;/strong&gt;, which is why you must hire a Realtor to accurately assess your home’s value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a final note, keep in mind that when you list your home on Zillow, you have the ability to alter its criteria and modify its Zestimate based on its condition. Don’t be afraid to take advantage of this and make sure your home’s valuation is as accurate as possible. If you need help with this, please let us know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. My team and I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-zillows-zestimates-accurate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-zillows-zestimates-accurate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>If Your Home Failed to Sell, Are You Sure It Was the Price?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LgdqGOqcP5I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you having trouble selling your home? Or did your listing expire recently without being sold?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My business partner Ryan McMillan and I are experts at helping people sell their homes after their previous agent was unsuccessful. Part of our daily schedule involves calling homeowners whose listings either expired or were canceled and asking them if they want to try again. Relisting a home that was previously on the market requires a different strategy, and we’ve perfected that craft over the last two years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we make these calls, a lot of former sellers blame price as the culprit behind their failed home sale. The shift in the market also gets some of the blame. However, some sellers also blame their agent, which leads us to believe that not all agents are the same in terms of doing everything they can to expose their sellers’ properties to the market—a big part of the home sale process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, &lt;strong&gt;when we research failed home sales, we oftentimes find out that the price was spot on, so the marketing or preparation couldn’t have been very good.&lt;/strong&gt; As you’ve heard me say before, there are three things that get a home sold: price, preparation, and exposure (i.e., the marketing your agent does to get the word out). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=About 35% of all home sellers who come off the market still need to sell, so if you fall into this category, please get in touch with us.%20http://localhost:4000/if-your-home-failed-to-sell-are-you-sure-it-was-the-price.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“About 35% of all home sellers who come off the market still need to sell, so if you fall into this category, please get in touch with us.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if the price isn’t to blame for your home failing to sell, you have to ask how your home showed, how accessible it was, how it “felt” as buyers came through it, and what your agent did to get the word out about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About 35% of all home sellers who come off the market still need to sell, so if you fall into this category, please get in touch with us.&lt;/strong&gt; We want to learn more about what was done to try and get your home sold and offer our expert advice and fill in the blanks. We want to know more about your goals, because nine times out of 10, we have a solution for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting in touch, in this case, is the hardest part, because owners of expired listings can get anywhere from 60 to 100 phone calls. This makes agents like us, who truly want to help you, a needle in the haystack. We know it can be overwhelming to have all this attention from other agents, but having options is good, and it’s worth a shot to give someone the chance to present a different approach to your home sale. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is, &lt;strong&gt;not all agents are created equal.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s no minimum standard in this industry—all you have to do to become a real estate agent is take a couple of classes and get your license. Some agents are great at what they do; others have no idea what they’re doing. Unless you interview multiple candidates to sell your home, you might get stuck with one who doesn’t do a good job for you. Fortunately, that’s where we come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. My team and I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 08:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/if-your-home-failed-to-sell-are-you-sure-it-was-the-price.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/if-your-home-failed-to-sell-are-you-sure-it-was-the-price.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
